(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-16T21:01:16.476410",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
それでは聞いてください
Now then, please listen.
ケ・セラ・ソラ！
Que Será Sora!
皆さん、今日は、ときのそら6周年突破記念に来てくれてありがとうございます！
Everyone, thank you so much for coming to celebrate Tokino Sora's 6th anniversary today!
おはよう 朝日に 今日も ご挨拶
Good morning, another greeting to the morning sun.
って あれ？ ウソ！ もう こんな時間！？
Wait, what? No way! It's already this late?!
午後から予定あるのに すぐに支度をしなきゃ
Even though I have plans this afternoon, I've got to get ready right away.
いってきまーす！
I'm heading out!
慌てて飛び出して 気付く
I rush out in a panic and realize,
こっちじゃなーいっ！ ここどこ！？
This isn't it! Where am I?!
助けてあん肝～っ！
Help me, Ankimo!
トラブルばっか転んで起きての毎日です
It's an everyday routine of tripping and getting back up through endless troubles.
何でも思い通りとかそんな美味しい話はないけど
There's no such convenient story where everything goes as planned, but
心の曇り空を晴らす合言葉 唱えたらね ほら、快晴でしょ？
if we chant the passphrase to clear our cloudy hearts, look, it's clear skies, right?
ずっと皆に届けたい 歌もダンスも元気も 同じ空の下 笑顔も分け合えるよ
I want to keep delivering songs, dances, and energy to everyone under the same sky, sharing our smiles.
ちょっと疲れちゃうときも 涙が出そうなときも
Even when I get a little tired, or when tears are about to fall,
いつもの魔法の言葉 今日も
today too, with our usual magic words—
ケ・セラ・セラのソラ
Que sera sera Sora!
ケ・セラ・ソラ！
Que Será Sora!
こんそめ今日も一日がんばろ カメラにマイクに…よし準備オッケー！
"Consome, let's do our best today too!" Cameras, microphone... Okay, ready!
お水もちゃんとするし 備えさえあれば嬉しいね
I've got my water ready, and being prepared is always great!
それじゃ今日は何をしようかな お歌に雑談に…あっ！ホラボコラブ！？
So what should I do today? Singing, chatting... Ah, HoloBoko Love?!
皆と笑い飛ばせば また明日も晴ればれだ！
If we laugh it off together, tomorrow will be bright and clear again!
よっしゃ！
Let's go!
ほっとため息こぼして ふと夜空を見上げたら
Letting out a sigh of relief, when I happened to look up at the night sky,
パッと満天の星たちが キラキラ瞬いてた
countless stars across the whole sky were twinkling brightly.
ずっと追いかけ続けたい 雲より高い夢でも もっと強く羽ばたいて 空まで駆けけてゆくよ
Even if it's a dream higher than the clouds that I want to keep chasing, I'll spread my wings stronger and race up to the sky.
そっと背中押すような温もりに包まれたら いつまでも止まらないよ 今日も、明日も、ずっと
Wrapped in a warmth that gently pushes my back, I'll never stop—today, tomorrow, and forever.
ケ・セラ・セラのソラ
Que sera sera Sora!
セーの！ ケ・セラ・ソラ！
Ready, set! Que Será Sora!
はーい、太陽発起で！
Hiii! With a burst of sunshine!
みなさーん！
Everyone!
見えてる〜？聞こえてる〜？
Can you see me? Can you hear me?
声、聞こえてますか〜？
Can you hear my voice?
初めまして、皆さんときのそらです！
Nice to meet you all, I'm Tokino Sora!
本日はここで路上ライブをさせていただけるということで、とても嬉しく思っています。
I'm so happy to do a street live here today!
ギターの村山☆潤さんに来ていただいて、一緒に路上でライブをしていきたいなと思っております。よろしくお願いします！
I've invited Jun Murayama on guitar to do a street live together.
いやぁ、皆さん聞こえてますか？ありがとうございます！
Yeah, can you guys hear me? Thank you so much!
初めてのアコースティックのライブでちょっと緊張してるんですけども、一時間頑張りますのでよろしくお願いします！
It's my first acoustic live so I'm a bit nervous, but I'll do my best!
次の曲も元気な曲を選びました。聞いてください、ピットして！マーマレード
I chose an energetic song for the next one. Please listen to this!
こんなに こんなに 叶えたいんだ
So much, so much, I want to make it come true,
強く願って願うだけ夢になった
dreaming just by wishing for it with all my might.
そうだから しっかりピットして！マーマレード
That's why, stay sharp and tight! Marmalade!
私頑張るよ頑張るからね
I'll do my best, I'll really work hard,
よっしゃ！ get up！ stand up！ run up！ grow up！
so alright! Get up! Stand up! Run up! Grow up!
ピッとして！マーマレード 作詞・作曲：田淵智也
[Song: Pitto shite! Marmalade - Lyrics & Music: Tomoya Tabuchi]
時々真面目で 時々おちゃらけて
Sometimes serious, sometimes playful,
時々リリしく ころころ変わる
sometimes dignified, constantly changing
空模様みたい どれもちゃんと空だし
like the sky's appearance, each one is truly the sky.
繋ぐ星と星のフレーズ 私と君のやり取りが線になる
The phrases of connecting stars, our banter forms a line.
素敵 ロマンチックで ドラマチック
Wonderful, romantic, and dramatic,
星座になって そして歌になる
becoming a constellation and then a song.
日進月歩って言えるほどたくましくできてないかもしれない
Maybe I haven't grown enough to call it daily progress,
せいぜいトライアルアンドエラーって感じか
maybe it's more like trial and error,
ハイメイミィ ねぇ これが私でいいかな？
Hey, is it alright if this is me?
いいでしょ そっとそっとじゃ揺がないの
It's fine, right? It won't shake easily with just a gentle touch.
こんくらいはラッタラッタラ笑えちゃうの
To this extent, I can just laugh, rah-ta-rah-ta!
笑えたら 次に行こう
Once we can smile, let's move on to the next.
気づいてる？ ちょっと成長してるよ！
Have you noticed? I've grown a bit!
キュートに キュートに 甘いだけじゃなくて
Not just cute, cute, and sweet,
ほのぼの ほのぼの ほろ苦いの
but also warm, cozy, and bittersweet.
だって合言葉は ピットして！マーマレード
Because our watchword is: Stay sharp! Marmalade!
君に会えるまで 次は何しよう？
Until I can see you, what shall we do next?
よっしゃ！ get up！ stand up！ run up！ grow up！
Alright! Get up! Stand up! Run up! Grow up!
細部に凝って真心込めて届けたいんだもん
I want to deliver it with meticulous care and sincerity.
一期一会かもしれないけど 繋がれ 空みたいに
It might be once-in-a-lifetime, but let's connect like the sky.
どんな服を着て街に出よう どんな髪型を試そう
What clothes should I wear? What hairstyle should I try?
一つ一つ君に見してほしいから…ほんとだよ？
I want you to see every single one of them... really!
君はどうだろう？もしもが
What about you? If "what ifs"
いっぱいっぱい連なって奇跡がいっぱいっぱい起きちゃって
pile up endlessly and miracles happen all over,
見たことない景色になる 君と私が作った景色だよ
it becomes a scenery created by you and me.
とってもとってもとってもとっても嬉しいんだ だからねほんとにほんとにありがとう、だ！
I'm so happy. That's why I'm truly, truly thankful!
君がくれるその声でマーマレード
With the voice you give me, Marmalade,
どんな色にでもなれる 紅茶に溶かすメロディーや
I can become any color. A melody melting into black tea
食パンに塗るリズムって 楽しさメーターは上がっていく
or rhythm on toast—our happiness meter keeps rising.
ススメ！ ススメ！ モット ユ ケ！
Go on! Go on! Go even further!
ねぇ、だから私は私でいたいの。
Hey, that's why I want to stay true to myself.
こんなに こんなに 叶えたくて
Wanting so much, so much to make it come true,
強く願って願うだけ夢になった
dreaming just by wishing for it with all my might.
なったからね 諦めるはずない
Since it became real, there's no way I'd give up.
そのステージきっとそこにある！
That stage is definitely right there!
一緒に一緒に目指したいの 景色を一緒に一緒に作りたいの
I want to aim for it together, I want to create the scenery.
そうだから しっかりピットして！マーマレード
That's why, stay sharp and tight! Marmalade!
私頑張るよ頑張るからね
I'll do my best, I'll really work hard,
よっしゃ！ get up！ stand up！ run up！ grow up！
so alright! Get up! Stand up! Run up! Grow up!
ってな感じで歌っていこう！ほんとに、ありがとう！
Let's sing with that feeling! Thank you so much!
ずーっとね ピットして！マーマレード
Forever, stay sharp! Marmalade!
こんなに こんなに 叶えたくて
Wanting so much, so much to make it come true,
強く願って願うだけ夢になったからね
dreaming just by wishing for it with all my might.
諦めるはずない そのステージきっとそこにある！
Since it became real, there's no way I'd give up.
一緒に一緒に目指したいの
I want to aim for it together,
景色を一緒に一緒に作りたいの
I want to create the scenery together with you.
悲しいしっかり ピッとして 守れの
Be sad, be firm, and protect me properly,
私が頑張るよ 頑張れるからね
I'll do my best, because I can do it.
よさげらそんなの
Something like that looks good,
ゴロゴロってな感じの歌っていこう
Let's sing a cozy, rolling sort of song.
本当にありがとう
Thank you so much.
ずっとねピッとして守れの
Always be firm and protect me,
みんなと今日7年目を一緒に お祝いすることができてとっても嬉しいです
I'm so happy to be able to celebrate our 7th year together with everyone today!
これからも一生懸命がんばってる空ね みんな これからも応援してくれますか？
Sora is working her hardest as always! Everyone, will you continue to support us?
たくさんたくさん 素敵な思い出で 作っていこうね！
Let's make lots and lots of wonderful memories together!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
というわけで今の曲は「ピッとして！マーマレード」でした！ おぱちゅぱちゅありがとうございます！ 本当に素敵なギターの演奏で 歌うことができて とても嬉しいです。
So that last song was 'Pitto shite! Marmalade'! Thank you very much for the pachi-pachi! I'm so happy to be able to sing with such a wonderful guitar performance.
そして次の曲 なーんとギターとの一対一での まあ 曲はラストになるんですけども 次の曲「チューチュル」という曲を歌っていただきます。
And for the next song... guitar and I, one-on-one—well, it's the last song, but the next song you'll hear is called 'Chu-Chu-Lu'.
なんとこの「チューチュル」っていう曲はアルバムのギターを村山亮さんがやってくださっています！
And amazingly, the guitar for this song 'Chu-Chu-Lu' on the album was played by Ryo Murayama!
一緒に 今日演奏することができてとても嬉しく思っています。
I'm so happy we could perform it together today.
まさかねアルバムの曲を ね、弾いてくださった方と本当に一緒にセッションできるなんて思っていなかったのでとても幸せです。
I never thought I'd actually get to jam with the person who played on the album song, so I'm truly blessed.
それでは最後のギターとの最後の曲お聞きください。「チューチュル」！
Now, please listen to the final song with guitar, 'Chu-Chu-Lu'!
chu-chu-lu…
chu-chu-lu...
男の子はいつでも強がりな生き物
Boys are creatures who always have to act tough,
弱さを嫌って涙は流さないの
Hating weakness and never shedding tears.
傷付からない人などこの世にいないから
Since there's no one in this world who never gets hurt,
たまには本当の声を聴かせてよ
At least sometimes, let me hear your true voice.
あなたはまだ不器用なウルフ
You're still a clumsy wolf,
もういいよ牙なんか捨てて
It's okay, drop those fangs and
深く深く愛してよ
Love me deeply, deeply.
酸いも甘いもメモリアル
The bitter and the sweet are all memoirs,
恋は怖くないんだよ
Love isn't something to fear.
あなたなら大丈夫
You'll be fine,
強く強くハグしてよ
So hug me tight, tight.
あの夜にさようならを…
Saying goodbye to that night...
いつもここで待ってるよ
I'll always be waiting right here,
だからもっと恐れずに愛してね
So love me even more without fear.
chu-chu-lu…
chu-chu-lu...
誰もがひとりだけじゃ居られない生き物
No one is a creature who can live entirely alone,
弱さを認め合い助け合うものよ
We acknowledge each other's weaknesses and help one another.
あたしもまだ不器用なエンジェル
I'm still a clumsy angel too,
お願いよ翼を広げて
I beg you, spread your wings
高く高く翔んでいくの
And soar high, high into the sky.
目指すはサンクチュアリ
Aiming for the sanctuary,
二人だけの楽園で
In a paradise just for the two of us.
甘い果実カプリ
Biting into sweet fruit,
手と手ギュッと繋いで
Holding hands tightly together,
じゃなきゃ離れちゃうからお…
Otherwise we might drift apart...
ずっとここで一緒だよ
We'll be together here forever,
だからもっといつでも愛してね
So love me even more at all times.
いつかできた傷跡に涙が染みいちゃうのなら
If tears ever seep into the scars made long ago,
笑顔のバンドエイドをあげるから前を向いてさあ行こう
I'll give you a smiling bandage, so look ahead and let's go.
深く深く愛してよ
Love me deeply, deeply.
何もかもがメモリアル
Everything is a memoir,
恋は怖くないでしょ？
Love isn't scary, is it?
あなたとあたしなら
If it's you and me.
強く強くハグしてよ
So hug me tight, tight.
あの夜にさようならを…
Saying goodbye to that night...
いつもここで待ってるよ
I'll always be waiting right here,
だからもっと恐れずに愛してね
So love me even more without fear.
chu-chu-Lu...
あたしもまだ 不器用なエンジェル
I'm still a clumsy angel,
お願いよ 翼を広げて
so please, spread your wings
高く高く飛んでくよ 目指すのはサンクチュアリ
and fly high up high, aiming for the sanctuary.
二人だけの楽園で 甘い果実カプリ
In a paradise just for us, biting into sweet fruit.
手と手ギュッと繋いでよ じゃなきゃ離れちゃうから
Hold my hands tight, or we'll drift apart!
ほらずっとここで一緒だよ だからもっと いつまでも
Look, we'll always be together here, so even more, forever...
愛してね
love me!
いつかできた傷跡に 涙が染みちゃうのなら
If tears seep into the scars left behind one day,
笑顔のバンドエイドをあげるから 前を向いてさあ行こう
I'll give you a smile bandage, so look forward and let's go!
深く深く愛してよ 何もかもがメモリアル
Love me deeply, deeply, everything is a memorial.
恋は怖くないでしょ あなたと私なら
Love isn't scary, is it? If it's you and me,
強く強く抱きしめてよ あの夜にさようなら
hold me tight, tight, and say goodbye to that night!
いつもここで待ってるよ だからもっと恐れずに
I'm always waiting right here, so without fear, even more...
愛してね
love me!
せーの、chu-chu-Lu... chu-chu-Lu...
Ready, chu-chu-lu... chu-chu-lu...
路上ライブ、ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much for the street live!
路上ライブの練習もしっかりできたし、また次のステージでも歌っていきたいな。
I practiced hard for the street live, and I want to sing on the next stage too!
りょうさん、またあとでー！
Ryo-san, see you later!
だいぶやってます。よろしくお願いします！
I've been at it for a while. Nice to meet you!
皆さんライブやってるので、ぜひ見に来てください。よろしくお願いします！
Everyone's doing live streams, so please come check them out. Thank you!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you very much!
今ライブやってます。よろしくお願いします！
I'm doing a live stream right now. Thank you!
これからライブをやるので、皆さん見に来ませんか？よろしくお願いします！
I'm going to do a live stream soon, so won't you come watch? Thank you!
よろしくお願いします。すごい、こんなライブだけじゃなくて、ダンスの特訓する施設もあるんだな。
Thank you! Wow, there's not just live houses, but also a facility for dance training.
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you!
よろしくお願いします！今度ライブやるんですけど、ぜひ見に来ませんか？いろいろ頑張ってるので、ぜひぜひよろしくお願いします！
Thank you! I'm doing a live stream soon, so won't you come watch? I'm working hard on various things, so please check it out!
あ、バイバーイ！見てくれてありがとうございます！
Ah, bye-bye! Thank you for watching!
よろしくお願いします！よろしくお願いします！
Thank you! Thank you!
すごーい！すごーい！
Amazing! Amazing!
この街の中で危なくないのかな？
Is it safe in this town?
よろしくお願いします！よろしくお願いします！
Thank you! Thank you!
ライブやりません...
I'm not doing a live...
ライブやります！お願いします！
I am doing a live! Thank you!
今度ライブやるんですけど ぜひ見に来てくれませんか？ よろしくお願いします！
I'm holding a live show soon, would you please come and watch? Thank you!
あ、ありがとうございます！ もし時間があったら ぜひ見に来てくださいね！
Ah, thank you so much! If you have time, please come check it out!
はい、というわけで、今度はこんな素敵なステージで歌うことができるようになりました！ありがとうございます！
Yes, and so, I'm now able to sing on such a wonderful stage! Thank you so much!
そして、もうすでに素敵な音を奏でてくださっている、ピアノのウィングさんです。よろしくお願いします！
And, playing such wonderful music already is our pianist, Wing-san. Thank you!
そんなウィングさんと一緒に演奏する曲はこちらです。『ポラリスソラリス』
The song we will perform together with Wing-san is this one: "Polaris Solaris".
星の数だけ ほら
Look, as many as the stars,
選択肢があったって story
there were choices, a story.
君の書いた 夢に出会えた キセキ感じて
Feeling the miracle of meeting the dream you wrote,
（北の空）7つの星（輝いて）
(The northern sky) Seven stars (shining bright)
いろんなことがあったよね 立ち止まることだって
We've been through so much, even stopping in our tracks,
それに意味があるって 教えてくれたね
and you taught me that there was meaning in it all.
ポラリス 旅をする者を いつも導いて
Polaris, always guiding travelers on their journey,
私にとって それが君だって 思うよ
I feel that you are that for me.
ポラリス 変わらずにいてね いつも見守って
Polaris, stay as you are, always watching over me,
永遠を信じたいよ 物語
I want to believe in eternity, our story.
神様がくれた
Given by God,
運命っていう名の story 離れ離れでも
a story called destiny, even if we are apart,
ひとつの奇跡信じて
believing in a single miracle,
高い空 5つの星
high in the sky, five stars
煌めいて
glittering above.
迷ってばかりの道だった ずっとね 怖くなかった
The path was full of hesitation, but I was never scared,
そばに君がいたから 勇気をくれたね
because you were by my side, giving me courage.
ソラリス 道しるべのように そっと佇んで
Solaris, standing gently like a signpost,
未来をちゃんと言つけられたんだ ありがとう
you helped me find the future properly, thank you.
ソラリス 素直になれるよ 君の言葉って
Solaris, I can be honest with your words,
続きを描きたいよ 物語
I want to draw the continuation of our story.
ah 点と点を繋いで
Ah, connecting the dots...
繋いで
Connecting...
あのね あのね 君のその目を見ると 明日を信じたいと そう思えるの
You know, you know, when I look into your eyes, I feel like I can believe in tomorrow.
でもね でもね 時は過ぎてしまうから 今を刻んで 忘れないでいて ずっと
But you know, but you know, time passes by so fast, so mark this present moment, never forget it, forever.
ポラリス 旅をする者を いつも導いて
Polaris, always guiding travelers on their journey,
私にとって それが君だって 思うよ
I feel that you are that for me.
ポラリス 変わらずにいてね いつも見守って
Polaris, stay as you are, always watching over me,
永遠を信じたいよ
I want to believe in eternity.
ソラリス 道しるべのように そっと佇んで
Solaris, standing gently like a signpost,
未来をちゃんと言つけられたんだ ありがとう
you helped me find the future properly, thank you.
ソラリス 素直になれるよ 君の言葉って
Solaris, I can be honest with your words,
続きを描きたいよ 物語
I want to draw the continuation of our story.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
本日は、えー、ここでのライブということで
Today, um, since this is a live performance here,
少し大人っぽく、そしてちょっとね、髪型も変えてきてみちゃいました。いかがだったでしょうか？
a bit more mature... and I also changed up my hairstyle. How was it?
そして、改めてご紹介します。ピアノのウィングさんです。
And let me introduce you once again. It's Wingu-san on the piano.
いや、もうとっても素敵な演奏で、
It's such a wonderful performance,
自分すごいね、なんかときめいちゃってずっと聞いていたいって感じだったんですけど、私が歌わないとね、ダメだなと思って、しっかり交わさせていただきました。
I was so charmed and wanted to keep listening, but I realized I had to sing too, so I made sure to join in properly.
本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you so much.
そして次の曲も、私にとって思い出深い曲です。
And the next song is also a deeply memorable one for me.
それはコトバカゼという曲なんですけど、私の初めて出したアルバムの中の曲で、たくさん聴いていただいていた曲だと思います。
It's a song called "Kotobakaze," a track from my very first album that I think many of you have listened to a lot.
それでは聴いてください、コトバカゼ。
Without further ado, please listen to "Kotobakaze."
胸の奥がくすぐったい
It tickles deep inside my chest,
本当ずるい人だな
you really are such a sly person.
無邪気すぎるその笑顔
That smile of yours is far too innocent,
友達だったのに
even though we were just friends.
金曜日付の街 ざわめく心も
The Friday night streets bustle, and my heart flutters too.
浮き足立って 今日ならば言えそうな気がした
Getting ahead of myself, I felt like today I might finally be able to say it.
コトバカゼ ふわり 頬をかすめ 恋はこんなふうに始まる
Words carried on the breeze, softly grazing my cheek—that's how love begins.
どこか懐かしい でも知らない かすかな匂い
A faint scent, somehow nostalgic yet unfamiliar.
冷たくしないでよ ねぇ あなたの秘密も知りたい
Don't be so cold... hey, I want to know your secrets too.
誰よりそばで微笑むよ ふわり 時には消えた物語 私だけに話してね
Smiling right by your side, softly... tell only me of the story that sometimes vanished.
繋がりくい電話だけ ちょっと気になってる
I've been a bit worried about that hard-to-reach phone call.
誕生日ももうすぐだって さりげなく伝えられた
You casually let me know your birthday is coming up soon.
好きだよと書いてみた ディスプレイ そのまま
I tried typing "I like you" and left the display just like that.
コトバカゼ ふわり 想い届け 愛はきっとこんなふうに知る
Words on the breeze, carrying my feelings—that's surely how love is known.
あの日少しだけ縮まった 距離 信じていいの？
Can I believe in the distance that shortened just a bit that day?
答えを訊かせてよ ねぇ あなたとの明日は来るの？
Let me hear your answer... hey, is there a tomorrow with you?
誰よりそばで涙はきらり どんな昨日をあなたは生きてきたの ねぇ
Tears sparkling brighter than anyone by your side—what kind of yesterdays have you lived through, hey?
どんな昨日をあなたは生きてきたの ねぇ コトバカゼ ふわり
What kind of yesterdays have you lived through, hey... Words on the breeze, softly...
胸の奥がくすぐったい
My chest tickles inside,
涙 きらり
with glistening tears.
胸の奥がくすぐったい
My chest tickles inside,
ほんのり 霞め
faintly blurring.
恋はこんなふうに始まる
That's how love begins,
どこかなつかしい でも知らないかすかな匂い
with a nostalgic yet unfamiliar scent.
冷たくしないでよ ねぇあなたの秘密も知りたい
Don't be cold; hey, I want to know your secrets too.
誰よりそばで微笑むよ ふわり
Smiling closer than anyone, softly...
時に消えた物語 あたしだけに話してね
Tell me alone the story that sometimes fades away.
ありがとうございました！ふふっ
Thank you very much! Heh.
ありがとうございました。コトバカゼでした。
Thank you. That was "Kotobakaze."
そして、次の曲が二人でライブするのは最後の曲です。
And, the next song we'll live stream together is our final song.
次の曲は「好き、泣いちゃいそうだ」という曲になります。
The next song is called "Suki, Naichaisou da."
「好き泣いちゃいそうだ」も、えっと私初めてのライブで最後に歌った曲で、みんなとの思い出がたくさん詰まった大事な曲です。
"Suki, Naichaisou da" is a very important song packed with memories of everyone, which I sang at the very end of my very first live.
それを今日このアコースティックで歌わせていただきますので、ぜひぜひ聴いていただけたら嬉しいです。
Today I'll be singing it acoustically, so I'd be so happy if you'd all listen to it.
それでは聞いてください。「好き、泣いちゃいそうだ」
Now then, please listen to "Suki, Naichaisou da."
意地悪な言葉を
Mean words,
わざと言ったりして
saying them on purpose,
欲張りになくらい 君を知りたいよ
I want to know you enough to be greedy.
恥ずかしがらないでよ いいでしょ？
Don't be shy, is that alright?
出会えた偶然を
The chance meeting we had
運命に変えたなら
If we turned it into destiny,
始まった恋は 加速していくの
the love that started will accelerate.
ブレーキはかけられないの
There's no putting on the brakes!
未完成なパズル 恋というピースを重ね合わせよう
Let's piece together the incomplete puzzle called love.
心は君で生まれてく いつだって
My heart is born from you, always.
そのままの君が好き
I love you just the way you are.
不器用で人見知り 無口だけど誰より優しい人ね
Clumsy and shy, but kinder than anyone else.
少し不器用なとこも 悠長じゃないとこも 強がるけど泣き虫なとこも 全部
A bit clumsy, laid-back, acting tough yet being a crybaby—all of it.
好き 泣いちゃいそうくらい
I love you so much I could almost cry.
まるでこの世界に たったふたりきりみたい
It's like we're the only two people in this world.
ふたつの影が
Two shadows
よりそう帰り道は
on our way back home together
なんだか少し切なくて
somehow feel a little bittersweet...
風になびく髪が
Hair fluttering in the wind
キミを追いかける
chases after you,
あと数センチの距離が胸を締め付けるの
and a distance of just a few centimeters tightens my chest.
いつだって届きそうで届かない 触れそうで触れられない
It feels like I can reach you, yet I can't... It feels like I can touch you, yet I can't...
近そうで遠いキミのその指先
Your fingertips look so close yet so far away.
溢れ出すこの想い今キミに伝えたら
If I were to tell you these overflowing feelings right now,
この手をぎゅっと握ってくれますか
would you hold my hand tightly?
初めて出会った瞬間に胸が熱くなって
The moment we first met, my heart grew warm,
きっとあの日からキミのことを…
and I'm sure from that day on, all I...
まだ一緒にいたくて ずっと傍にいたくて
I still want to be with you, I want to stay by your side forever.
キミも同じ気持ちでいてくれるのかな
I wonder if you feel the same way too.
胸の痛みはきっと好きの合図なんだね
The pain in my chest is surely a sign of love.
痛くて苦しくてこんなにも温かい
It hurts so much, it's so agonizing, yet so warm.
好き、泣いちゃいそうだ
I love you... I feel like I'm going to cry.
みなさん、ピアノとのセッション盛り上がっていただけたでしょうか？
Did you all enjoy our session with the piano?
パチパチありがとうございます！見えてるよ、ありがとうございます！
Round of applause, thank you! I see you, thank you!
路地、そしてこの素敵な場所ときて、
Alleyways, and coming to this wonderful place...
でも私の夢はアイドルなので、いつかステージで歌いたいと思っています！
But since my dream is to be an idol, I hope to someday sing on stage!
次も来てくれるかな？
Will you come next time too?
あのステージでみんな会おうね！
Let's meet everyone on that stage!
リングさん、ありがとうございました！
Ring-san, thank you very much!
そしてみんな後でね！
And everyone, see you later!
くまちゃん、さっきは見てくれてありがとうございました！
Kumachan, thank you for watching earlier!
落ち着いて見れましたか？
Were you able to watch calmly?
あ、ところです、私なんか美容部員っぽいがあるなと思っていて、
Oh, by the way, I felt like you had a bit of a beauty advisor vibe,
この前街でなんか測定とかバレエとか練習してたりしませんでした？
didn't you happen to be in town practicing measurements, ballet, or something recently?
あ、エプしてますよね？私あソコの時にチラシ配ってて、
Ah, you were doing it, right? I was handing out flyers over there at that time,
いや、私もね、実はダンスとかをちょっと練習してるんですよ。
and well, actually, I've been practicing dancing a bit too.
あそこまでそう、バレエとかはできないんですけど、もしよかったら一緒に練習してたりしませんか？
I can't do ballet all the way like that, but if you'd like, would you want to practice together sometime?
あ、いいですか？
Ah, is that okay?
もしよければこれからずっと一緒に頑張っていきましょう！
If you're willing, let's keep doing our best together from now on!
あ、嬉しい！
Ah, I'm so happy!
じゃあこれからぜひよろしくお願いします！
Well then, I look forward to working with you from now on!
一緒に頑張ろう！
Let's do our best together!
あ、よろしくね！
Ah, nice to meet you!
今度ライブやります！よろしくお願いします！
We're having a live show soon! Thank you for your support!
ライブいかがですか？よろしくお願いします！
How about the live? We look forward to it!
よろしくお願いします！よろしくお願いします！ライブやります！
Thank you! Thank you! We're holding a live show!
よろしくお願いします
Pleased to make your acquaintance.
Looking forward to it!
こんにちは！
Hello!
ライブやります！
I'm holding a live!
よろしくお願いします！
I'd love for you to come!
Looking forward to it!
よろしくお願いします！
こんにちは！
Hello!
ライブやります！
I'm holding a live!
よろしくお願いします！
Looking forward to it!
こんにちは！
Hello!
ライブいかがですか？
How about checking out my live?
よろしくお願いします！
Please check it out!
こんにちは！
Hello!
今度ライブやるんですが、いかがですか？
I'm holding a live concert soon, how about it?
この子も一緒にビラを配ってくれてます。
This little guy is helping me hand out flyers too.
絶対素敵なライブにするので、ぜひ見に来てくれませんか？
It's going to be amazing, so won't you come see it?
見に来てくれませんか？
Won't you come see it?
こっそり、あの、
Secretly, um...
よろしくお願いします。
I'd really appreciate it.
あ、ありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Oh, thank you so much! Thank you!
やったね！
We did it!
ありがとうございます！よろしくお願いします！
Thank you so much! Looking forward to it!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
よろしくお願いします！
Looking forward to it!
同じ未来を見ていた
We were looking at the same future,
あの夢手にしたい
and we want to make that dream ours.
それぞれ違ったココロで走れgo
Running with our respective hearts, go!
どこを見ても真っ暗な
No matter where I looked, it was pitch dark,
場所に見生えてた
but something was sprouting in that place.
ほんの小さな希望に
Captivated by just a tiny bit of hope,
この瞳奪われた
my eyes were stolen away.
不安で揺れる心を上手くチューニングして
Tuning my heart that trembled with anxiety,
ほんの小さな勇気を振り絞っていたよ
I mustered up a tiny bit of courage.
諦めの文字デリートして進む
Deleting the word "give up," I move forward.
苦しいときも
Even in painful times,
もう私はひとりじゃないから
I am no longer alone anymore,
だからもっと夢追いかけたい
so I want to chase my dreams even more.
ワクワク止まらない想像超えてく
Excitement won't stop, going beyond imagination,
世界見せてあげるアクセスしてみたい
I'll show you the world, I want to access it.
後悔なんてそうさせない
I won't let you have any regrets.
それぞれ違ったココロで走れgo
Running with our respective hearts, go!
仮想の空に輝く眩しい想いは
The dazzling feelings shining in the virtual sky,
見たことのない光を現実に届けるよ
deliver an unseen light to reality.
いつも聴こえるエールはここにキャプチャして
Capturing the cheers I always hear right here,
また新しい光を探したくなるよ
I start wanting to search for a new light.
君の笑顔は保存して進む
Saving your smile, I move forward.
悲しいときに見返すよ力が湧くから
Looking back at it when I'm sad gives me strength.
胸を張って夢追いかけたい奇跡の物語一緒に作ろう
I want to chase my dreams and create a story of miracles!
終わらない夢を誰ひとり欠かせない
An endless dream where not a single person can be missing,
愛が舞ったこの世界それぞれ違ったココロで彩れ
color this world where love danced with our respective hearts.
悲しいときも寂しいときもある
There are sad times and lonely times,
信じ合えるものがある忘れずにこの鼓動鳴らし続けたい
and I want to keep this heartbeat ringing without forgetting.
終わらない世界に溢れ出るよ笑顔達
Smiles overflowing into an endless world,
憧れの舞台立ちたいらしく輝きたい
I want to stand on the stage of my dreams and shine.
時に涙してまた笑い合いたい
Sometimes shedding tears, and wanting to laugh together again.
同じ未来を見ていたあの夢手にしたい
Looking at the same future, we want to make that dream ours.
踏み出そう奇跡の一歩を
Let's take that first miraculous step forward!
息切らせて夢追いかけたいワクワク止まらない
Out of breath, wanting to chase dreams, excitement won't stop,
想像超えてく世界見せてあげる
going beyond imagination, I'll show you the world.
アクセスしてみたい後悔なんてそうさせない
I want to access it, and I won't let you have any regrets.
それぞれ違ったココロで走れgo
Running with our respective hearts, go!
胸を張って夢追いかけたい奇跡のストーリー一緒に作ろう
I want to chase my dreams and create a story of miracles!
終わらない夢を誰ひとり欠かせない
An endless dream where not a single person can be missing,
愛が舞ったこの世界それぞれ違ったココロで彩れ
color this world where love danced with our respective hearts.
色どーれ！
Color it!
みんな！ありがとね！歌うことができたよ！
Everyone! Thank you so much! I was able to sing!
同じ未来を見ていたい
I want to see the same future,
あの夢手にしたい
I want to make that dream come true.
それぞれ違った
With our different hearts,
ココロで走れGO
let's run with GO!
どこを見ていても真っ暗な場所に芽生えてた
No matter where I looked, it was pitch dark.
ほんの小さな希望にこの瞳奪われた
My eyes were captured by a tiny hope.
不安で揺れる心を上手くチューニングして
Tuning my trembling heart just right,
ほんの小さな勇気を振り絞っていたよ
I mustered up a tiny bit of courage.
諦めの文字デリートして進む
Deleting the word "give up," I'll move forward.
苦しいときも
Even when times are tough,
もう私はひとりじゃないから
I'm no longer alone.
だからもっと夢追いかけたい
So I want to chase my dreams even more,
ワクワク止まらない
The excitement just won't stop.
想像越えてく世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a world beyond imagination!
アクセスしてみたい
I want to access it,
後悔なんてそうさせない
I won't let there be any regrets.
それぞれ違った
With our different hearts,
ココロで走れGO
let's run with GO!
仮想の空に輝く眩しい想いは
Dazzling feelings shining in a virtual sky,
見たことのない光をリアルに届けるよ
delivering an unseen light to reality.
いつも聴こえるエールはここにキャプチャーして
Capturing every cheer we always hear right here,
また新しい光を探したくなるよ
I want to search out a brand new light.
君の笑顔は保存して進む
I'll save your smile and move forward,
悲しいときに見返すよ力が湧くから
Looking back when I'm sad gives me strength.
胸を張って夢追いかけたい
Standing proud, I want to chase my dream,
奇跡のストーリー
a miraculous story.
一緒に作ろう
Let's create it together,
終わらない夢を
an unending dream,
誰一人欠ばせない
leaving no one behind.
愛が舞ったこの世界
This world where love has danced,
それぞれ違ったココロで彩れ
let's color it with our own hearts.
はい！というわけで、ついに！
Alright everyone, we finally did it!
アリーナで！歌いました！
We performed in Arena!
そして、先ほど一緒にそしてくださった
And earlier, those who sang with us...
りょうさんと、ウイングさんと
Ryo-san, Wing-san,
そしてあんきもも一緒です！
and Anki-mono-san were all together!
というわけで、ここからは4人で
So, from here on, the four of us
歌っていきたいなと思っております！
will keep on singing together!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
いやもうこんなに豪華な感じで歌わせていただけるなんて
To be able to sing with such a gorgeous feel,
本当に幸せです。
I'm truly happy.
みんなも生の演奏を楽しんでくれてるかな？
I wonder if everyone's enjoying the live performance, too?
次の曲も全体曲から選びました。
The next song was also chosen from the main setlist.
自分の中では一番難しい曲で
It's one of the hardest songs for me,
とってもなんか練習した曲でもあるので
and one I've practiced a lot.
温かく見てもらえたら嬉しいです。
So I'd be super happy if you watch it warmly.
次の曲聴いてください、「Prism Melody」。
Please listen to the next song, "Prism Melody".
そうさずっと！
That's right, forever!
僕らの奇跡が途切れないように歌うんだ
We're singing so that our miracle
もっと高く！
won't ever fade away,
大きな声で
with an even higher, louder voice!
聴こえてた? 何かが始まるサイン
Did you hear it? The sign that something is beginning.
集まって気付けば和音を奏でた
Gathering together, before I knew it, we were playing a harmony.
夢に見るだけじゃもう足りないでしょ?
Just dreaming about it isn't enough anymore, is it?
キミを待ってる世界があるよ
There's a world out there waiting for you!
楽しい予感にほら飛び乗っちゃえばいい
Come on, let's just jump right into this joyful premonition.
トキメキは止められないから走ろ!
The excitement is unstoppable, so let's run!
連れていくよ! 光の真ん中 夢の先へ
Lead us away, right into the middle of the light, beyond our dreams!
羽ばたける勇気はキミの願い
The courage to spread our wings is your wish.
皆で繋いだこの奇跡が
This miracle we've all woven together
途切れないように歌うんだ
we'll sing it so it never, ever ends,
もっと高く! 大きな声で
with an even higher, louder voice!
答えとか理屈に惑わされてさまよっても
Even when we get lost in answers and logic,
戻ってこられる場所があったんだ
there was a place we could always return to.
地図にない道ゆく僕らの旅
Our journey goes where no map shows the way,
願いだけが道標だよ
and our only signpost is our wish.
夢の色が変わっても変わらないメロディ
Even if the colors of our dreams change, the melody remains the same.
キミのために僕らのために歌おう!
Let's sing it for you, for us!
そうさきっと! 僕らの奇跡は終わらないよ
Yes, for sure, our miracle will never end!
涙さえキッカケに変えていこう
Let's turn even our tears into our starting point.
信じてくれる仲間と一緒に
Together with friends we can truly believe in,
どこへだって飛び出していこう
let's leap out to anywhere at all!
もっと遠く! 空を越えて
Going further, far beyond the skies!
未来の僕らにまだ見ぬキミに伝えたいこと沢山あるんだ
There is still so much we want to tell our future selves and the "yous" we haven't met yet.
迎えたイマは当たり前なんかじゃない
Welcoming this present moment isn't just something to be expected—
翼を広げさあ今飛ぼう! take my hand!!
so spread your wings and let's fly right now, take my hand!
そうさずっと僕らの奇跡が
Yes, forever, our miracle
途切れないように歌うんだ
will keep singing so it never fades.
もっと高く大きな声で
With a higher, louder voice!
聞こえていた？何かが始まるサイン
Did you hear it? The sign of a new beginning.
未来の僕らにまだ見ぬキミに伝えたいことたくさんあるんだ
We have so much to tell our future selves and you.
迎えたいまは当たり前なんかじゃない翼を広げさあ今飛ぼう
Spread your wings, now let's fly!
飛ぼう
Let's fly!
take my hand 連れていくよ光の真中
Take my hand, I'll lead you to the center of light.
夢の先へ羽ばたける勇気はキミの願い
The courage to soar beyond dreams is your wish.
みんなで繋いだこの奇跡が途切れないように歌うんだ
I'll sing so this miracle we wove never fades.
もっと高く大きな声で
With a higher, louder voice!
ボクらの未来ロードでどこまでも響け
Resound forever down our future road!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
プリズムメロディでした！
That was "Prism Melody"!
そしてここで、お知らせがあります！
And now, I have an announcement to make!
おお、ありがとうございます！というわけで、そのお知らせがこちらです！
Oh, thank you very much! Here is the announcement!
ときのそら 活動6周年記念グッズが出ます！
Tokino Sora 6th Anniversary goods are out!
いろんなセットがあるので、一つずつ見ていこうと思います。
There are various sets, let's look one by one.
まずはこちら、「そらと一緒に抱き枕カバー」です！
First is the "Dakimakura Cover with Sora".
そして次がこちら、「あんきもスリッパ」です！
And next is the "Ankimo Slippers"!
そしてこちら、シチュエーションボイスです！
And here is the scenario voice.
活動6周年記念フルセットということで、
As for the 6th Anniversary Full Set,
公式ファンクラブのアプリができました！
The official fan club app is now available!
そして最後にお知らせがあります！
And finally, here is an announcement!
本日23時にリハーサル映像がアップされます！
Rehearsal footage will be released tonight at 23:00!
それでは コメントが 見えなくなってしまいましたが
Well, I can't see the comments anymore, but
みんな 喜んでくれてるかな? ありがとうございます。
I wonder if everyone's happy? Thank you very much.
えー、次で最後の曲になります。本当に本当に最後の曲です。
Um, the next song will be the last one. Really, truly the last song.
え、最後の曲も、やっぱり全体曲の中から選ばさせていただきました。
Um, I chose the final song from all the group songs as well.
みんなでパレードをして終わっていきたいよねということで、最後の曲はこちらにしたいと思います。
Since I want us all to finish with a parade, I'd like this to be the last song.
みんなのコメント見えてるよ! ありがとう!
I can see everyone's comments! Thank you!
それでは聴いてください。「Our Bright Parade」！
Now then, please listen to "Our Bright Parade"!
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! It's shining bright,
呼び合う声を 合図に
Taking the calling voices as our cue.
Parade, Parade, Parade! 探しに行く
Parade, parade, parade! We're going to search,
スタートは 何度だって
No matter how many times we start anew.
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! It's shining bright,
悔しさも 愛しさも 連れておいでよ
Bring along your regrets and your affection too.
ただ 独り言 綴った
I weave lonely words into echoes,
ただ 始まりたくて 走った
I ran because I wanted to begin.
遠く 暗がりに灯った
Far away, a light lit up the darkness,
それは 眩しすぎた名前
It was a name that shone too brightly,
それは 優しすぎる思い出もっと
Memories that are far too gentle,
近づけと 手を伸ばした 思いがけず 結び合った
Reaching out to get closer, unexpectedly we united.
ほら 今 迷子 は “僕 等” に なった
Look, now the lost ones have become "us."
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! It's shining bright,
悔しさも 愛しさも 連れておいでよ
Bring along your regrets and your affection too.
風 夢 羽 飛び立てるさ
Wind, dreams, and wings will let you take flight.
ささやかな祈りは 光 終わりなし 兆し
These silent prayers become an endless light and sign.
君を見つけたこと 胸を張れるよ
I can stand tall knowing I found you.
ここから これから Our Bright Parade, Parade!
From here, from now on, our bright parade, parade!
まだ 頼りない予感を
With uncertain feelings still lingering,
歌おう 恥ずかしかなんてないよ
Let's sing—there's nothing to be embarrassed about.
誰も ほどけない イマジナリー
An imaginary world no one can unravel,
いつか また逢える おまじない
A spell to ensure we'll meet again someday.
あの日 ゼロに始まった ストーリー
The story that started from zero on that day,
数え切れない 言葉の葉
Countless leaves of words,
数えるような 想いじゃないさ
Not feelings you can simply count.
ほら 今 “僕 等” を 一つ と 呼ぼう
Look, now let's call "us" one.
Parade, Parade, Parade! 美しいんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! It's all so beautiful,
許し合える 刹那 夜は きらめく
Moments of forgiveness make the night sparkle.
雨、晴れ、カレイド またとない空
Rain, shine, kaleidoscope—a once-in-a-lifetime sky.
相応しい旅路とは 君と在る ことさ
A fitting journey means being right here with you.
君 と 在る こと なんだ
Yes, it means being with you.
「ただいま」を聞けば 「おかえり」って叫ぶよ
When I hear "I'm home," I'll shout "Welcome back."
当たり前じゃないか
Isn't that just natural?
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! It's shining bright,
暗がりを満たすのは 君だ 僕だ
Filling the darkness are you and I.
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! It's shining bright,
悔しさも 愛しさも 連れておいでよ
Bring along your regrets and your affection too.
風 夢 羽 飛び立てるさ
Wind, dreams, and wings will let you take flight.
ささやかな祈りは 光 終わりなし 兆し
These silent prayers become an endless light and sign.
君と飛び込んでいく 素敵なスタートさ
Diving in together with you—what a wonderful start.
ここから これから Our Bright Parade, Parade!
From here, from now on, our bright parade, parade!
Our Bright Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ
Our Bright Parade, Parade! Shine bright!
本当に 本当に ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much, truly!
せーのっ！
Ready, go!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
このあとはアフターパーティーで、会おうねー！
See you at the after-party right after this!